Now, with text
deposit, you can manage
your accounts from
literally anywhere.
You can bank on it.
You can
bank on us...
Sequoia Liberty.
Okay, yes, they do
sound similar.
They're
the same song.
Someone stole my song
and turned it into a jingle.
You said you never
played this at a show?
I have a little studio space
in Alphabet City.
I do everything there.
But it's soundproofed.
When I'm writing,
I work alone.
Could you just
excuse me for a moment?
Watson.
- What are you doing?
- Having worked through the night
at various pursuits, I am now
attempting to fall asleep.
Obviously.
You familiar with the surrealist
works of Salvador Dalí?
Yes, of course
I am familiar with Dalí.
Well, we share the same
opinion of sleep.
Namely that it is
a waste of time.
There may exist,
however, a moment
at the boundary between
working and sleeping
which holds some
utility. He would use
a similar method
to catch himself
the instant he fell asleep
and record glimpses
into his subconscious mind.
And I'm trying to train
my own subconscious
to solve more
impenetrable problems.
Though I do realize
that from the outside it seems
no more pragmatic that a visit
to the Delphic Oracle.
From the outside,
it makes a lot of noise.
I'm meeting with
a client downstairs.
A woman, no? If she's
the one playing
the guitar, you might
want to suggest that a tuning
is in order.
Does her case intrigue?
Do you require
my assistance?
I require a little quiet.
That's all.
I shall continue my experiment
on a higher floor.
Captain.
Hey, I've got two detectives
from the 3-5 here.
They want to talk to you about
a homicide they're working.
Yes, of course.
Watson is otherwise engaged,
but I can be there
in about 30 minutes.
I'll see you then.
Holmes, this is Detective Demps
- and McShane.
- Gentlemen.
Heard a lot about you
the last couple years.
Despite my best efforts,
I assure you.
How can I help you?
Maria Gutierrez.
She went missing
a little over three years ago.
Last week her remains
were discovered
by a city worker in a vacant lot
next to Thomas Jefferson Park.
Erosion had partially
- uncovered the grave.
- M.E. said
she died from blunt force
trauma to the head.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Ms. Gutierrez worked
in a custodial profession,
night shifts,
mostly.
You, uh, you saying
you knew her?
Certainly not.
The hair on her right forearm
is a distinctly lighter shade
than that on her left. Um,
ammonia and bleach, of course,
whiten body hair. Her natural
hair color resumes at a line
where one imagines
she wore rubber gloves.
Her skin tone is also
several shades lighter
than that of her
immediate relatives,
indicating a more
nocturnal lifestyle.
No, no way.
You had to know her.
You indicated that you were familiar
with my methods.
Yeah, well, we heard
you knew a few tricks.
Not tricks.
You sure you don't know her?
Never laid eyes
on her before?
This is not a consultation,
it's an interrogation.
So, would you like to tell me
why you consider me a suspect?
Mm-hmm?
We found this
in the victim's purse.
It's a receipt
from a coffee shop
two blocks
from your residence,
dated the day
that Maria disappeared.
Want to tell us again
how you don't know her?
I know what you're thinking.
S. Holmes...
that could be a lot of people.
Maybe there's a Steve Holmes
out there, or a Sally.
But we showed it to our
handwriting expert at Q-DOC.
I could have
saved you the trouble.
I'm the author of that note.
There is no doubt.
Oh, then you lied when you said
you didn't know Maria Gutierrez.
I did not lie.
I do not recall her face
and I have no memory of writing
- to her.
- You saying you have amnesia?
Of a sort.
During the period
in question... late 2011,
when Ms. Gutierrez disappeared...
I was quite addicted
to narcotics.
A great variety
of them,
in fact.
Blackouts were not uncommon.
And on this night in particular,
the 7th of December, 2011?
I do not believe
I could be much clearer.
I have no recollection
of this woman
or anything that might
have happened to her.
Guys,
- it's a note.
- Received
by our Vic the day she
disappeared, one your consultant
just admitted he wrote.
She was a cleaner,
maybe he wanted to hire her.
Before we came here, you said
this was a waste of time,
you knew your guy.
I do.
Did you know about
the blackouts?
You asked for five minutes,
I gave you five minutes.
If anything
else occurs
to my consultant,
I'm sure he'll be in touch.
Hey. I realized
I needed one of these to cook.
What's wrong?
Had I not deprived myself
of sleep these last few nights,
perhaps I would have realized
what was happening sooner.
Captain should have told you.
It would have
been indefensible
for him to show me
special consideration.
But he has every confidence
that the detectives
- are wasting their time.
- They are.
I wrote that note.
I was without
a phone at the time.
I used street urchins
to bring my correspondence
to and fro.
And that makes you a killer?
I feel confident
that the moral maths
of my character
would have prevented me
from committing a murder
even in the most
altered of states.
However,
some of the drugs
I used during that period
made me quite paranoid.
Others caused hallucinations.
The unfortunate truth is
that however improbable
certain things may be
with respect to this crime,
nothing's impossible.
It was a few months after Irene.
You thought she was dead.
You were using more.
It began as practical attempt
to improve my mental horsepower.
I expected to find connections
that others had missed.
But as my failures mounted,
so too did my cravings.
And distraction turned
to crass dependence.
And so began
the downward spiral.
You know we're gonna
figure this out.
Well, I've been asked
not to interfere.
You say that like you
haven't heard it before.
Never been a suspect before.
Besides, we're at
a grave disadvantage.
Ordinarily, the police would
share their files with us.
We'd have access to evidence,
we'd have access
to the victim's remains.
I can't even say how I knew her.
Then that's where we'll start.
Watson...
We know her name.
You said you saw pictures
of her with her family.
I'll talk to them.
I promised the captain.
I didn't.
You stay here, dig into your
files, see if her name pops up.
You think I knew her
through my work.
How do you
know anyone?
Maybe she wanted to hire you
or she was a witness
in a case you were working.
Or maybe Gregson was right...
you just needed someone
to clean this place.
Whatever the connection is,
you did not kill that woman.
Uh, Mrs. Sandoval?
Hi, I'm Joan Watson.
I know who you are.
Um, the detectives
from the 35th told you
- about me.
- And your partner.
I am so sorry for your loss.
I can imagine how difficult
this week has been for you, but
I promise you I am
only here because
I want to help
find the person who killed
- your sister.
- I don't want to talk to you.
Please, do you have any idea
how Maria and Sherlock
would have known each other?
What do you mean how they
He was going through
a difficult time,
he's having trouble remembering.
I would want to forget
killing Maria, too.
- Mrs. Sandoval...
- No.
You ask me how they knew
each other. I don't know.
She was indocumentado.
Illegal.
She stayed out of trouble,
she-she did her work.
Went to church.
But in the end,
it didn't matter.
Trouble found her.
Please, don't
come here again.
All right, check the
stitching, get a feel for it.
Huh? Nice, right?
You're not gonna
find quality like that on
Canal Street.
What, you don't like the color?
You want to see it in red?
I got it in red.
Oh, ladies, come on,
come on, don't
be like that. Hey, I got
a special going on today...
two for one.
What, do you got a date
with Godzilla or something?
Those women are from
China, not Japan.
Though the racism worked,
either way.
Don't suppose I can
interest you in a handbag?
That depends. Does your supplier
always spell “Prada”
with two Ds?
Been a long time.
Not long enough, Oscar.
Not nearly.
But I need your help
with something.
I can't believe
it's been three years.
Yes, well,
time flies
when you're on heroin.
You look good.
You clean?
I am.
Good for you. Hey!
Hey! Beat it!
Yeah, scram!
We had a good
thing going on.
- We were a good team.
- Actually,
we were not a team.
I was a consumer of narcotics,
and you were someone
with access
to pharmaceutical-grade product.
You don't call that a team?
I do not.
Yes, you spent a good deal
of time at my home,
but that was
because you were prone
to rendering yourself
unconscious.
How did it all go so wrong?
Well, if memory serves, Oscar,
you let yourself in one day
and made off with
several thousand dollars' worth
of rare books
and computer equipment.
Well, you said
you needed my help?
You may recall, in the weeks
prior to our parting ways,
my drug use
became quite profound.
Well, the price was some equally
profound holes in my memory.
And no one spent more time with
me during that period than you.
I would like to know
if the name Maria Gutierrez
means anything to you.
There's evidence to suggest
I had plans to meet with her
- in December of 2011...
- Sherlock,
of course I remember her. Maria?
From the circus.
Dark hair, big...
No, no, no. Th-That's Marena.
She was one of my paramours.
Maria, Oscar.
Maria Gutierrez.
Do you remember the name or not?
Look, man, I'm sorry.
You're not the only one who has
trouble remembering those days.
Ah, well, this was fun.
Catching up.
I got to go.
Maybe we can do it again
sometime.
- Watson.
- I just got home. Where are you?
I thought a constitutional
might jog my memory.
It did not.
How did you do?
To be honest, not good.
The guys at the 35th told
Maria's family
and friends about me.
No one was in a talking mood.
My files were equally fruitless.
If Ms. Gutierrez was connected
to a crime I was investigating,
I failed to make a note of it.
Is it possible
this is some sort of frame-up?
The body was so well hidden,
it took three years to discover.
If it was a frame-up,
it was a very poor one.
You know, I've been reading up
on articles
from when she disappeared
in 2011.
I know it's not the same
as looking at police files,
but something jumped out at me.
She put a lot of hours in
at her church's soup kitchen.
You think
she may have come across
some shady characters there?
Marcus is running down a list
of their frequent fliers.
- You brought the detective into this?
- Of course I did.
He's gonna let us know
if anyone has a record.
I'm almost home.
We'll discuss the matter
in person.
Sherlock Holmes?
Do I know you?
Let's go. Come on. We got to go.
Come on.
Let's go!
You know, I'd have
an easier time examining you
- if you would put down your phone.
- I imagine you would. Fortunately
for the both of us, my wounds
are entirely superficial.
- There could be internal damage.
- There is not.
Well, if you're in such great
shape, why did you come here?
I enjoy hospitals.
Especially in the middle
of the night.
Doctor, if my ears
do not deceive me,
a real patient
has just arrived.
A man with a lightbulb
in an unfortunate place.
- Right.
- Hey, we need you.
Foreign body impaction. Bad one.
If you require
assistance,
you will not find smaller or
steadier hands than Watson's.
So, are you gonna call
the police, or should I?
- There's no need.
- You were targeted.
One of the men
called you by name.
And it can't be a coincidence
that you were jumped
the same day you were questioned
about a homicide.
I think it is a coincidence.
Though I do not disagree
that the two events
are connected.
Does the name Prentice Gutierrez
ring a bell?
Maria's brother.
I saw his name mentioned
in one of the articles I read.
I couldn't track him down today.
Probably because he was busy
planning an ambush.
How do you know
he was one of the...
There are few circumstances
more amenable
to picking a man's
pocket than a thrashing.
It is better to be the
thrasher, obviously,
but beggars can't be choosers.
An Internet search
of Mr. Gutierrez
revealed nothing more than
his connection to his sister.
But a police intranet search,
however...
He was arrested for burgling
a home in November of 2011.
That's just one month
before Maria disappeared.
He insisted to anyone who would
listen that he was innocent.
And you posited earlier
that Maria wished to hire me
as a detective.
She believed him.
You were supposed to find
the person who really did it.
Prentice.
I know you?
We had a brief
physical relationship.
Perhaps this will jog
your memory.
I lost this a couple
of days ago. Thanks.
Mr. Gutierrez,
I bear you no ill will.
You learned my name
from the detectives
investigating Maria's murder,
and you took matters
into your own hands.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Of course
you do.
Just like you know
you're on parole
for that burglary charge
in 2011.
An assault charge could violate
you back to prison.
It'd be worth it, though, wouldn't it?
Hurting the man who hurt Maria?
The problem is, neither of us
can say with any certainty
that I am that man.
Right.
Because you don't remember.
Or at least that's the story
you tried to sell
to my other sister.
The burglary.
You said you didn't do it.
You got any idea who did?
What the hell does that have
to do with anything?
We're investigating
the possibility that Maria
wanted help finding that person.
He would've had motive
to stop her.
You stay away from me
and my family.
Both of you.
We'll go back to the station.
We'll look into burglaries
that were committed
around that time.
We might be able to find
a suspect without his help.
So, we're onto something,
though, aren't we?
You know who committed
the burglary.
You have until I finish
replacing these brake pads.
If you're still here
when I turn around,
I'm the one who's gonna
be calling the cops.
Mr. Gutierrez...
- Come on. Let's go.
- It occurs to me, you know,
that any one of these tools
could've been the end of me
last night.
But you attacked me
with fists
and with booted feet.
So you didn't want to kill me.
You just wanted to hurt me.
Do you want to do it again?
What are you
talking about?
I'm talking
about reciprocity.
about quid pro quo.
If you submit to my questions...
I'll submit to a blow
from this wrench.
You're not certain
that I hurt Maria, are you?
If you're open to suggestions,
I offer my hand.
Come on. You're gonna break
any number of bones.
The pain's gonna be
excruciating.
Sherlock...
I did the burglary.
I did it.
And Maria knew it. I told her.
So you're wrong
about her wanting you to find
the person who really did it.
If she wanted your help,
it didn't have anything to do
with that.
Can you think
of anyone who would've wanted
to hurt her?
You know she cleaned, right?
The year she went
missing, there was a guy
she worked for who owned
a couple of buildings in Queens,
and one of them was being rented
by a-a councilman
who was running for reelection.
Uh, Barclay.
She told me that someone
there was hitting on her,
that-that it made
her uncomfortable.
- Did she tell you the man's name?
- No.
Because she was worried that
I might do something stupid.
And you know what?
She was right. I would have.
I told the police
after she went missing.
They said they looked into it
but that it was a dead end,
that the guy had an alibi.
According to them.
Councilman Barclay would appear
as a friend of the department.
Perhaps the police
who were investigating
Prentice's claim that his sister
was being harassed
didn't encounter
a dead end
so much as a "do not enter."
What are you saying? That this
was some sort of cover-up?
Well, if there was,
it would be a turn up for us.
Conspiracies are fraught.
One secret versus
many keepers.
There'd be no shortage
of new leads.
You were gonna let him do it,
weren't you?
Maria's brother...
you were gonna let him
hit you with that wrench.
Excuse me.
The councilman will see you now.
I didn't know Maria well,
but she was sweet.
I spent a lot of late nights
here during the campaign.
I'd see her
when she'd come in to clean,
and she'd ask
how I was holding up.
When... Maria
was reported missing,
I'd hoped that she'd
just gone back to her country,
but... I'd been around
too many cops for too many years
- to really believe that.
- It's our understanding that
one of your reelection team was
briefly considered a suspect.
That's right.
I'm sorry, it's just...
I've been advised
not to talk to you.
You are aware that
I'm a person of interest.
Even though Maria
wasn't a member
of my team, what happened
to her affected us.
I've been keeping myself
- apprised.
- I'm confused.
Why did you agree to see us?
Because...
I'm also a fan.
The administrative
hearing last year,
you had to make your case
to stay on with the department.
A lot of people wanted you gone,
but I looked into you.
And the more I discovered,
the more impressed I was.
If you say
you didn't hurt Maria,
I'm inclined to believe you.
- Well, thank you.
- It's true,
M-Maria was being
harassed by someone
who worked here.
My deputy press secretary...
a man named Tom Graves.
He propositioned her
on several occasions.
I wasn't aware
until the police questioned him
about her disappearance.
We were told he was cleared.
He was out of the state
the night Maria went missing.
I was told there was a video
of him at his hotel.
I still fired him, of course.
Hmm. So much for the cover-up.
Like I said,
I have a sense for how you work.
I know you make a habit
of catching things
other people have missed.
I'll give you
everything
I gave the police
in 2011.
If Tom got away
with something...
maybe you'll be able
to figure out how.
Hey.
I thought you said you were going
for a walk to clear your head.
It should trouble you
how often you believe that.
What is this?
Upon our
verification
of the alibi of Tom Graves,
randy press secretary,
I've decided to attack this case
as I would any other.
It is not
utterly devoid of fact,
and there is even
a strong suspect.
Is that a picture of you?
I took that one
by accident several years ago.
I was in an altered state,
and I mishandled my phone.
God only knows what
I intended to photograph.
If you really want
to beat yourself up...
You think this is
an exercise in self-pity.
I think this is an Olympics
in self-pity.
First you tell
Prentice Gutierrez
he can break your hand,
and now you're
sitting in the dark staring at
an old photograph of yourself.
You did not kill that woman...
stop acting like you did.
You are positive I didn't do it.
- Of course I am.
- How?
Because I know you.
Yes. Better than anyone.
But let make one thing
perfectly clear.
You did not know him.
You never
met him.
So you're Dr. Jekyll now
and he's Mr. Hyde?
You continue to misunderstand.
At that point in my life,
I did not plumb down
into some dark part of myself.
I detached from myself, from
all that was essential to me.
To say that you
can guess what I was
capable of is illogical...
I was a different person.
And the fact that I remember
so little from that time
has been nothing
but a tremendous relief to me
until now!
I'm sorry, okay?
I know it hurts,
but there is nothing
you can say that's gonna
convince me that
you killed that woman.
Let's adhere
to our sunniest theory
for a moment, shall we?
That my note to Maria Gutierrez
was not, in fact,
an invitation to murder,
but an agreement
to lend my help as a detective.
What if she knew
she was in danger?
And what if I missed something
that my sober self
would have observed
in an instant
that might have saved her life?
Would you still consider
my hands blood-free?
Hey, Marcus.
Hey. I ran that list of regulars
from the soup kitchen where
Maria Gutierrez volunteered.
Got back about two dozen names
with arrest records.
I just e-mailed them over.
No one jumps out, but they all
seem worth talking to.
I cleared my morning
to help out.
Figured I'll take
the first ten or 12 guys.
Thank you, Detective.
That won't be necessary.
Why did you
just do that?
Because a meaningful connection
between Maria Gutierrez
and myself
has just materialized.
I recognize a name
on this list.
Go away.
Are you deaf? I said go away!
Aw, man,
you busted my door.
That might be the highlight
of this encounter, Oscar.
You lied to me.
You told me you did not know Maria
Gutierrez... it's come to my attention
that you were a regular at the
soup kitchen where she worked.
What?
St. Luke's Parish.
You tell me
you never supped there.
Yeah, yeah, sure I did,
I still do, but...
Come on, man, what, you think I
remember every person that ever
- worked there?
- I think a connection between you
and the woman I'm accused of
murdering is quite remarkable.
I think the fact
that you lied to me
about it is rather suspicious.
Come on, Sherlock, please,
- I'm sick.
- You're in withdrawal,
and that's good...
it's going to make it
more difficult for you
to deceive me again.
Where were you
the night Maria disappeared?
Oh, what, you think I did it?
Come on, Sherlock,
that's crazy.
Tell us about the note, Oscar.
- What note?!
- The one found
in Maria's purse...
the one that said
Sherlock was
gonna meet with her.
Did you trick him
into writing it?
You really don't remember,
do you?
Remember what?
You killed her, man.
You!
Yeah, I bet
you feel
pretty big
these last couple of years...
off the horse,
back on the job, all clean
and pretty.
Only you weren't,
were you?
No, you had dirt
on you! Blood!
Yeah, you always thought
you were better than me,
even when you were using,
but now you know... you're not.
You're worse.
I may be a bum and a junkie,
but I never killed anyone.
You will tell me
everything that you know.
All right,
yeah, man.
Yeah, sure.
You know, get a pen.
Let me make it easier for you
to pin it all on me.
You want my advice?
Let it go.
If all the police have
is a note...
count your blessings.
- Watson.
- We're leaving?
- Yes.
- This is not over.
It'd better be,
or trust me,
you're gonna spend
the rest of your life in a cell!
You haven't said much
since we got back.
I have a plan,
if you want to hear it.
We meet
with the captain first thing.
We tell him everything.
He brings Oscar in.
If Oscar's still sick,
it might not
take him long to crack.
Your plan is flawed.
He will not crack
because he did not do it.
He's been convicted
of purse-snatching and assault.
Probably tried to rip Maria off;
she fought back.
No.
His withdrawal symptoms,
as predicted,
made him utterly readable.
He was telling the truth
when he said I did it.
- Are you saying you believe him?
- I'm saying
I believe that he believes
I'm the guilty party.
He's either correct
or he's laboring
under a horrific
misconception.
Either way, he did not do it.
He will not crack.
Your plan is flawed.
Sorry if I upset you
this morning.
At the garage with the wrench.
It's okay.
It's a form of torture...
having to swim
through my old life.
I know that over the years,
you've suffered
your own travails
and you can relate
to a profound sense of guilt.
You cannot relate
to a profound sense of shame.
Detectives.
Mr. Holmes.
What is it? What's going on?
Isn't it obvious?
I'm being arrested.
Sherlock Holmes,
you're under arrest for
the murder of Maria Gutierrez.
You have the right
to remain silent
and refuse
to answer questions.
Anything you say
may be used against you
in a court of law.
All I could get
out of my buddy at the 3-5
was that some new witness
came forward.
Someone who said
they saw Sherlock kill Maria?
No, someone who says
they heard him threaten her life
a few days
before she disappeared.
I don't believe it.
The guys at
the 3-5 do.
- Right now, that's all that matters.
- I don't suppose
you were able
to put a name to the witness.
They're keeping
everything
under wraps. Like they should.
Holmes is not a cop,
but he's close.
They got to protect their case.
You have any luck with that list
I sent you last night?
We did.
Sherlock knew one of the names.
We talked to the guy.
- Is it someone you like for the murder?
- No.
But I'm pretty sure another
conversation is in order.
You don't look sick anymore,
Oscar.
I'm guessing you scored last night?
- You know, I never got your name.
- Joan.
I work with Sherlock.
Hi, Joan. Uh...
you here with some money
for a new door?
No, I'm here because I know
you're the witness
who got Sherlock arrested.
- What?
- Okay,
I want to know
what you told them right now.
Wait a second. Wait a second.
Sherlock's in jail?
Okay, don't, Oscar. You threatened him,
you told him he was gonna go to prison.
Oh, no. No, this is bad.
If you don't start telling the
truth, it's gonna get worse.
No, you don't get it. It's bad
for both of us, him and me.
Look, I said what I said
to scare him off.
The last thing I wanted
was for him to get arrested.
How is this bad for you?
I didn't do it, okay? He did.
- But he can take me down with him.
- Listen,
whatever really happened three
years ago, I will help you.
But first you need to tell me
why you think
Sherlock killed Maria.
I'll do you one better.
I'll show you.
Sherlock was right.
I did know Maria
from the soup kitchen.
She was beautiful.
I was a bum, and
she talked to me.
She talked to all of us.
I bragged a couple times that my
buddy was this big private eye.
She'd laugh, and then, one
day, she said she had a problem.
She asked if he could help.
- What was the problem?
- I don't know.
She would only
tell Sherlock.
So I went to him,
said I knew someone
who wanted to talk to him.
But he was in a bad way,
had been for weeks.
But he said he would meet her.
That's what the note was about?
The one found in
Maria's purse?
I don't know.
I guess.
Few days later,
I hear she's missing.
I go see Sherlock,
and he's wasted.
Can't wake him up.
And I'm nervous,
looking around
for more of whatever he's on.
Instead of his stash...
I find this.
Look, for what it's worth,
I don't think he meant to do it.
No, I just think
he was confused.
That happens sometimes.
One night I crashed with him,
I woke up, and he had
a knife to my throat.
Kept saying I was
a spy or something.
So, you hid these
here to protect him?
No, protect us.
I mean, I had a record.
I set up the meeting.
Think the cops won't come
after me as an accessory?
Yeah, so I took the bag
and, you know, a few things
that I could pawn,
and that was that.
I didn't see Sherlock again,
you know, until a few days ago.
Why didn't you just
get rid of the bag?
In case he ever came after me
for the stuff I stole
or to blame me
for what he did to Maria.
Hey, this was insurance.
Look, I'm sorry if that's not
what you wanted to hear,
but that's the truth.
I believe you.
Who are you calling?
Friend at the 11th.
You're gonna give this stuff
to the cops?
Hey, this shirt,
these pants...
they're the end of Sherlock.
You get that, right?
Actually, I think you're wrong.
I think they're gonna help him.
It's interesting, Watson,
spending the night in a cell.
I'm reminded that there are
good places for bad people.
Is that what you are now...
a bad person?
You've been to see Oscar.
Or you yourself
have been cooking heroin?
May I assume he's the
witness who told Detectives
Demps and McShane that I had
threatened Maria Gutierrez?
Actually, no.
He took this clothing
out of your place
a few days
after Maria disappeared.
Do you recognize them?
He thought you were wearing them
when you killed her,
but the sizes are wrong, and
the bloodstain pattern suggests
it was worn by someone
who committed a stabbing murder.
Maria died from blunt force
trauma to the skull.
You believe these are evidence
for an entirely different crime?
Maria told Oscar
she had a problem
and needed your help.
What if these were the problem?
Maybe they were at your place
because she gave them to you.
Maybe she knew about a murder
and got her hands on these.
Instead of bringing them
to the police,
she brought them to me,
heroin addict.
She was in the country
illegally and probably
worried about being deported.
Either way,
the killer found her,
Oscar took the clothes, and
you forgot you ever had them.
Just like you forgot about her.
Now Marcus and the captain
are looking into
stabbing deaths around the time
that she disappeared.
If we can find one that connects
back to her in any way...
a person that she knew, a place
where she spent a lot of time...
We might be able
to identify the real killer.
Your search will need to extend
to missing persons, as well.
If the killer hid the body
of his second victim,
Maria, it stands to reason he
also hid the body of his first.
Good news is, I might be able
to narrow that search
considerably for you.
What do you mean?
I was wrong.
I do recognize that shirt,
but not from three years ago.
The shirt has a double
cuff at the wrist.
The inlay on the buttons
is rather distinctive.
I've seen it recently.
I believe I know
who's behind all of this.
Councilman Barclay,
Tommy Gregson.
We met at a fund-raiser
a few years ago?
Ah, of course.
It's great to
see you again.
This is Detective Bell, and, uh,
- you know Ms. Watson.
- Of course.
There have been some new
developments in Maria's case.
We were hoping
we could discuss them with you.
Oh, tell me,
how can I help you?
A new witness
came forward last night.
He told police that he saw
Sherlock threaten Maria.
Oh, I hadn't heard.
Is the name Eddie
Bynum familiar to you?
I don't think so.
Why?
Because he's the witness.
He's also a site foreman
at Hatano Construction.
You know his boss,
Matthew Hatano.
They've handled the majority
of the Section 8 housing
developments in your
district the last few years.
Okay.
You steered a lot
of business
their way...
a couple of million at least.
If you had asked for a favor,
it'd be hard to say no.
I'm sorry.
I'm not following.
You don't know
Eddie Bynum. Okay.
What about Kelsey Prior?
Captain, I'm not sure
what this is,
but I'd like the three of you
to leave.
I need to place a call
to the commissioner.
If it's about us being here,
I'll save you the trouble.
- He knows.
- Kelsey Prior, Councilman.
You knew her, right?
She was a...
She was the wife
of a dear friend.
She was stabbed to
death in her home
in December, 2011.
It looked like a robbery gone
wrong, only it wasn't, was it?
Friend of hers thought
she was having an affair.
The detectives
who caught the case
couldn't find
any evidence of that.
We're guessing
you were pretty careful.
You had a lot to lose,
after all;
you were trying
to get reelected.
This is ridiculous.
Why don't you tell
us what happened?
Did she try to break it off?
Threaten
to go public?
Whatever it was,
you stabbed
her to death.
You had her blood all over you,
so instead of going home
to your wife,
you came here, to your office.
Told our colleagues
you spend a lot of nights here.
Probably had
a change of clothes.
Problem was,
you weren't alone.
Maria saw you getting rid
of the evidence, right?
Maybe you took it somewhere
and she followed.
Or maybe you dumped it
right here at the office.
Either way, she got
her hands on it.
You must've gotten nervous.
Decided you wanted to dispose of
the bloody clothes
some other way.
But when you went to retrieve
them, they were gone.
You thought of Maria.
- I'm calling my attorney.
- Before you do,
you should know
we have the clothes.
Sherlock
remembered
seeing them in a picture when
we were here the other day.
They don't connect you
to Maria's murder,
but they do connect you
to Kelsey's.
Four years ago,
police were able
to determine that
the killer's hand
slipped over the hilt of
the knife when he stabbed her.
He cut himself, leaving
blood at the scene.
When we compel
a DNA sample from you,
it's going to match.
Between that
and Eddie Bynum,
who I'm confident
is going to tell us
his boss put him up to giving
a false statement last night,
you might want
to tell your attorney
he's got his work
cut out for him.
The witness, Eddie Bynum,
folded pretty quickly.
So did Matthew Hatano.
When the councilman saw
the writing on the wall,
he told us everything.
He did kill Kelsey Prior,
and then, a few nights later,
he killed Maria.
The same night I met with her.
Was he following her?
He never knew
about you.
What he did,
he did a few hours later.
He went to her place.
She wasn't there,
so he called her.
He said he could
explain everything.
It was just one
big misunderstanding.
He told her if she
agreed to meet with him,
he could pull some strings
at the department.
Get her brother
out from under
the burglary charge
he was facing.
She believed him.
He picked her up at the
Frobisher Motel in Bayside.
I remembered the name from
some of your old case files.
I know that on
at least two occasions,
you stashed witnesses there
you thought were in danger.
The other night,
you said you were worried
you might have
missed something.
Something you would've noticed
if you were sober.
I don't think
you missed anything.
No, I just forgot someone
who needed my help.
Where are you going?
Walk.
It should
trouble me, right?
How often I believe that?
Oscar.
Sherlock.
Hey.
I heard you
got sprung.
Have you ever tried stopping?
Stopping what?
Come on, man.
Rehab's for quitters.
And it would be a shame,
would it not?
Quitting all of this?
What's that?
It's contact information
for Hemdale
Rehabilitation Facility.
You now have a standing
reservation there.
Oh, that's...
that's very nice of you.
No, actually, it's not.
I despise you, Oscar.
I always have.
You were never
more than
a sickening means
to a sickening end.
I would excise you
from my life entirely,
but I bear
some responsibility for you.
Three years ago,
you helped steer me
to the lowest point
of my existence.
But a case could be made that
I did the same for you, so...
I came here to make amends.
Hemdale, Oscar.
Go there, get better...
or don't.
But mark my words,
if I do see you again,
make sure it's because
you're ready
to make reparations of your own.
Hey.
You're gonna see me again,
you can count on it.
Only this time, you're gonna be
the one coming back to me.
To where I am.
And it won't be for any amends.